# MARY E. FARNER New York, NY

github.com/maryfarner18 medium.com/@maryfarner maryfarner.me

Software engineer experienced in JS and Ruby on Rails based web development, with background in CS and experience in finance and fitness. Possess strong people and project management skills to help small teams drive growth and success.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, SQLite, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, React, Java, Python, C, C++, SQL, HTML, CSS, PHP

#### TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

# Critter Crossing [Demo] [code]

My personal website to display my resume and experiences

• Implemented a JS React front end to display local JSON data

# Rezzemay [Demo] [code]

App to automatically generate an online resume given user inputs

- Built JS React frontend with integration of Semantic UI and custom CSS
- Implemented a Ruby on Rails backend API to manage user authentication and data storage

# Fitnest (Currently Working) [code]

Software to help manage a gym, from members, to personal training, to group fitness

• Created JS React frontend with Redux and Semantic UI libraries. Utilized Ruby on Rails backend for data API and

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Project Manager: Chelsea Piers, New York, NY

2019 - 2019

• Managed enterprise-wide technology turnaround including assessment of the user experience and web presence, financial reporting and back office software tools, and business operational software.

#### **Regional Group Fitness Director:** Chelsea Piers Fitness, New York, NY

2018 - 2019

- Led all operations and programming for the Group Fitness program at both locations in Manhattan and Brooklyn.
- Assisted in Chelsea Piers' expansion as a member of the original management team in Brooklyn.
- Managed 80+ instructors and three full-time employees with oversight of hiring and payroll processes.

#### **FX Forwards Trader, Analyst:** Bank of America Merrill Lynch, New York, NY

2017 - 2018

- Funded daily FX positions and supported senior traders in market-making, pricing, reporting, and risk management.
- Passed all requisite FINRA Licensing Exams (Series 7 and Series 63).

#### Associate Computer Scientist: US Air Force Research Lab, Information Directorate, Rome, NY

2016 - 2017

- Processed and analyzed data to provide for informed decision-making and increased security in AF-wide operations.
- Held a Top-Secret security clearance.

#### **Teaching Assistant, CS50:** Yale Computer Science Department, New Haven, CT

2015 - 2016

• Led teaching sections covering topics from lectures, held office hours assisting students with debugging and conceptualization of homework assignments, graded and provided feedback on students' assignments and tests.

# Operations Research Intern: US Air Force HQ Materiel Command, Wright Patterson AFB

2014 - 2015

• Created a database with a graphical user interface for the storage and management of future Air Force aircraft and technology that was deployed base-wide and eventually adopted into the Air Force-wide wargaming community.

#### **EDUCATION**

### Flatiron School, New York, NY

2019 - 2020

Web Development Immersive Course

# Yale University, New Haven, CT

2012 - 2016

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science & Mathematics - *GPA*: 3.54/4.00 Women's Varsity Crew, walk-on, 2015 & 2016 Ivy League Champion